<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<library lang="eng">
  <resource id="0">
    <topic>faith</topic>
    <reference url="https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/study/scriptures/bofm/alma/32.21?lang=eng#p21">Alma 32:21</reference>
    <body>
      <image url="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/gospel-library/manual/09410/1032863.jpg" />
      <video url="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dRvBgxKkbB0" />
      <title>Alma 32</title>
      <highlight verse="21">And now as I said concerning faith—faith is not to have a perfect knowledge of things; therefore if ye have faith ye hope for things which are not seen, which are true.</highlight>
    </body>
  </resource>
  <resource id="1">
    <topic>faith</topic>
    <reference url="https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/study/scriptures/nt/matt/17.20?lang=eng#p20">Matthew 17:20</reference>
    <body>
      <title>Matthew 17</title>
      <highlight verse="20">And Jesus said unto them, Because of your unbelief: for verily I say unto you, If ye have faith as a grain of mustard seed, ye shall say unto this mountain, Remove hence to yonder place; and it shall remove; and nothing shall be impossible unto you.</highlight>
    </body>
  </resource>
  <resource id="2">
    <topic>faith</topic>
    <topic>obedience</topic>
    <reference url="https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/study/scriptures/nt/james/2.14-24?lang=eng#p14">James 2:14-24</reference>
    <body>
      <title>James 2</title>
      <highlight verse="14">What doth it profit, my brethren, though a man say he hath faith, and have not works? can faith save him?</highlight>
      <highlight verse="17">Even so faith, if it hath not works, is dead, being alone.</highlight>
      <highlight verse="18">Yea, a man may say, Thou hast faith, and I have works: shew me thy faith without thy works, and I will shew thee my faith by my works.</highlight>
      <highlight verse="19">Thou believest that there is one God; thou doest well: the devils also believe, and tremble.</highlight>
      <highlight verse="24">Ye see then how that by works a man is justified, and not by faith only.</highlight>
    </body>
  </resource>
  <resource id="3">
    <topic>diligence</topic>
    <reference url="https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/study/scriptures/bofm/moro/9.6?lang=eng#p6">Moroni 9:6</reference>
    <body>
      <title>Moroni 9</title>
      <highlight verse="6">And now, my beloved son, notwithstanding their hardness, let us labor diligently; for if we should cease to labor, we should be brought under condemnation; for we have a labor to perform whilst in this tabernacle of clay, that we may conquer the enemy of all righteousness, and rest our souls in the kingdom of God.</highlight>
    </body>
  </resource>
  <resource id="8">
    <topic>charity</topic>
    <topic>hope</topic>
    <reference url="https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/study/scriptures/bofm/moro/7.40-48?lang=eng#p40">Moroni 7:40-48</reference>
    <body>
      <title>Moroni 7</title>
      <highlight verse="40">And again, my beloved brethren, I would speak unto you concerning hope. How is it that ye can attain unto faith, save ye shall have hope?</highlight>
      <highlight verse="41">And what is it that ye shall hope for? Behold I say unto you that ye shall have hope through the atonement of Christ and the power of his resurrection, to be raised unto life eternal, and this because of your faith in him according to the promise.</highlight>
      <highlight verse="42">Wherefore, if a man have faith he must needs have hope; for without faith there cannot be any hope.</highlight>
      <highlight verse="43">And again, behold I say unto you that he cannot have faith and hope, save he shall be meek, and lowly of heart.</highlight>
      <highlight verse="44">If so, his faith and hope is vain, for none is acceptable before God, save the meek and lowly in heart; and if a man be meek and lowly in heart, and confesses by the power of the Holy Ghost that Jesus is the Christ, he must needs have charity; for if he have not charity he is nothing; wherefore he must needs have charity.</highlight>
      <highlight verse="45">And charity suffereth long, and is kind, and envieth not, and is not puffed up, seeketh not her own, is not easily provoked, thinketh no evil, and rejoiceth not in iniquity but rejoiceth in the truth, beareth all things, believeth all things, hopeth all things, endureth all things.</highlight>
      <highlight verse="46">Wherefore, my beloved brethren, if ye have not charity, ye are nothing, for charity never faileth. Wherefore, cleave unto charity, which is the greatest of all, for all things must fail—</highlight>
      <highlight verse="47">But charity is the pure love of Christ, and it endureth forever; and whoso is found possessed of it at the last day, it shall be well with him.</highlight>
      <highlight verse="48">Wherefore, my beloved brethren, pray unto the Father with all the energy of heart, that ye may be filled with this love, which he hath bestowed upon all who are true followers of his Son, Jesus Christ; that ye may become the sons of God; that when he shall appear we shall be like him, for we shall see him as he is; that we may have this hope; that we may be purified even as he is pure. Amen.</highlight>
    </body>
  </resource>
  <resource id="5">
    <topic>faith</topic>
    <topic>opposition</topic>
    <reference url="https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/study/scriptures/bofm/ether/12.6?lang=eng#p6">Ether 12:6</reference>
    <body>
      <title>Ether 12</title>
      <highlight verse="6">And now, I, Moroni, would speak somewhat concerning these things; I would show unto the world that faith is things which are hoped for and not seen; wherefore, dispute not because ye see not, for ye receive no witness until after the trial of your faith.</highlight>
    </body>
  </resource>
  <resource id="6">
    <topic>diligence</topic>
    <reference url="https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/study/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/4.26-27?lang=eng#p26">Mosiah 4:26-27</reference>
    <body>
      <title>Mosiah 4</title>
      <highlight verse="26">And now, for the sake of these things which I have spoken unto you—that is, for the sake of retaining a remission of your sins from day to day, that ye may walk guiltless before God—I would that ye should impart of your substance to the poor, every man according to that which he hath, such as feeding the hungry, clothing the naked, visiting the sick and administering to their relief, both spiritually and temporally, according to their wants.</highlight>
      <highlight verse="27">And see that all these things are done in wisdom and order; for it is not requisite that a man should run faster than he has strength. And again, it is expedient that he should be diligent, that thereby he might win the prize; therefore, all things must be done in order.</highlight>
    </body>
  </resource>
  <resource id="7">
    <topic>diligence</topic>
    <reference url="https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/study/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/127.4?lang=eng#p4">D&amp;C 127:4</reference>
    <body>
      <title>Doctrine and Covenants 127</title>
      <highlight verse="4">And again, verily thus saith the Lord: Let the work of my temple, and all the works which I have appointed unto you, be continued on and not cease; and let your diligence, and your perseverance, and patience, and your works be redoubled, and you shall in nowise lose your reward, saith the Lord of Hosts. And if they persecute you, so persecuted they the prophets and righteous men that were before you. For all this there is a reward in heaven.</highlight>
    </body>
  </resource>
  <resource id="9">
    <topic>charity</topic>
    <reference url="https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/study/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/19.9?lang=eng#p9">1 Nephi 19:9</reference>
    <body>
      <title>1 Nephi 19</title>
      <highlight verse="9">And the world, because of their iniquity, shall judge him to be a thing of naught; wherefore they scourge him, and he suffereth it; and they smite him, and he suffereth it. Yea, they spit upon him, and he suffereth it, because of his loving kindness and his long-suffering towards the children of men.</highlight>
    </body>
  </resource>
  <resource id="10">
    <topic>charity</topic>
    <reference url="https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/study/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/2.17?lang=eng#p17">Mosiah 2:17</reference>
    <body>
      <title>Mosiah 2</title>
      <highlight verse="17">And behold, I tell you these things that ye may learn wisdom; that ye may learn that when ye are in the service of your fellow beings ye are only in the service of your God.</highlight>
    </body>
  </resource>
  <resource id="11">
    <topic>humility</topic>
    <topic>knowledge</topic>
    <reference url="https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/study/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/9.28-29?lang=eng#p28">2 Nephi 9:28-29</reference>
    <body>
      <title>2 Nephi 9</title>
      <highlight verse="28">O that cunning plan of the evil one! O the vainness, and the frailties, and the foolishness of men! When they are learned they think they are wise, and they hearken not unto the counsel of God, for they set it aside, supposing they know of themselves, wherefore, their wisdom is foolishness and it profiteth them not. And they shall perish.</highlight>
      <highlight verse="29">But to be learned is good if they hearken unto the counsels of God.</highlight>
    </body>
  </resource>
  <resource id="12">
    <topic>humility</topic>
    <reference url="https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/study/scriptures/bofm/ether/12.27?lang=eng#p27">Ether 12:27</reference>
    <body>
      <title>Ether 12</title>
      <highlight verse="27">And if men come unto me I will show unto them their weakness. I give unto men weakness that they may be humble; and my grace is sufficient for all men that humble themselves before me; for if they humble themselves before me, and have faith in me, then will I make weak things become strong unto them.</highlight>
    </body>
  </resource>
  <resource id="13">
    <topic>humility</topic>
    <reference url="https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/study/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/16.1-3?lang=eng#p1">1 Nephi 16:1-3</reference>
    <body>
      <title>1 Nephi 16</title>
      <highlight verse="1">And now it came to pass that after I, Nephi, had made an end of speaking to my brethren, behold they said unto me: Thou hast declared unto us hard things, more than we are able to bear.</highlight>
      <highlight verse="2">And it came to pass that I said unto them that I knew that I had spoken hard things against the wicked, according to the truth; and the righteous have I justified, and testified that they should be lifted up at the last day; wherefore, the guilty taketh the truth to be hard, for it cutteth them to the very center.</highlight>
      <highlight verse="3">And now my brethren, if ye were righteous and were willing to hearken to the truth, and give heed unto it, that ye might walk uprightly before God, then ye would not murmur because of the truth, and say: Thou speakest hard things against us.</highlight>
    </body>
  </resource>
  <resource id="14">
    <topic>hope</topic>
    <reference url="https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/study/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/31.20?lang=eng#p20">2 Nephi 31:20</reference>
    <body>
      <title>2 Nephi 31</title>
      <highlight verse="20">Wherefore, ye must press forward with a steadfastness in Christ, having a perfect brightness of hope, and a love of God and of all men. Wherefore, if ye shall press forward, feasting upon the word of Christ, and endure to the end, behold, thus saith the Father: Ye shall have eternal life.</highlight>
    </body>
  </resource>
  <resource id="16">
    <topic>hope</topic>
    <reference url="https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/study/scriptures/nt/rom/8.24-25?lang=eng#p24">Romans 8:24-25</reference>
    <body>
      <title>Romans 8</title>
      <highlight verse="24">For we are saved by hope: but hope that is seen is not hope: for what a man seeth, why doth he yet hope for?</highlight>
      <highlight verse="25">But if we hope for that we see not, then do we with patience wait for it.</highlight>
    </body>
  </resource>
  <resource id="17">
    <topic>knowledge</topic>
    <reference url="https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/study/scriptures/bofm/alma/17.2-3?lang=eng#p2">Alma 17:2-3</reference>
    <body>
      <title>Alma 17</title>
      <highlight verse="2">Now these sons of Mosiah were with Alma at the time the angel first appeared unto him; therefore Alma did rejoice exceedingly to see his brethren; and what added more to his joy, they were still his brethren in the Lord; yea, and they had waxed strong in the knowledge of the truth; for they were men of a sound understanding and they had searched the scriptures diligently, that they might know the word of God.</highlight>
      <highlight verse="3">But this is not all; they had given themselves to much prayer, and fasting; therefore they had the spirit of prophecy, and the spirit of revelation, and when they taught, they taught with power and authority of God.</highlight>
    </body>
  </resource>
  <resource id="18">
    <topic>knowledge</topic>
    <reference url="https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/study/scriptures/bofm/moro/10.3-5?lang=eng#p3">Moroni 10:3-5</reference>
    <body>
      <title>Moroni 10</title>
      <highlight verse="3">Behold, I would exhort you that when ye shall read these things, if it be wisdom in God that ye should read them, that ye would remember how merciful the Lord hath been unto the children of men, from the creation of Adam even down until the time that ye shall receive these things, and ponder it in your hearts.</highlight>
      <highlight verse="4">And when ye shall receive these things, I would exhort you that ye would ask God, the Eternal Father, in the name of Christ, if these things are not true; and if ye shall ask with a sincere heart, with real intent, having faith in Christ, he will manifest the truth of it unto you, by the power of the Holy Ghost.</highlight>
      <highlight verse="5">And by the power of the Holy Ghost ye may know the truth of all things.</highlight>
    </body>
  </resource>
  <resource id="19">
    <topic>knowledge</topic>
    <reference url="https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/study/scriptures/nt/john/14.23-26?lang=eng#p23">John 14:23-26</reference>
    <body>
      <title>John 14</title>
      <highlight verse="23">Jesus answered and said unto him, If a man love me, he will keep my words: and my Father will love him, and we will come unto him, and make our abode with him.</highlight>
      <highlight verse="24">He that loveth me not keepeth not my sayings: and the word which ye hear is not mine, but the Father’s which sent me.</highlight>
      <highlight verse="25">These things have I spoken unto you, being yet present with you.</highlight>
      <highlight verse="26">But the Comforter, which is the Holy Ghost, whom the Father will send in my name, he shall teach you all things, and bring all things to your remembrance, whatsoever I have said unto you.</highlight>
    </body>
  </resource>
  <resource id="20">
    <topic>humility</topic>
    <reference url="https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/study/general-conference/2010/10/pride-and-the-priesthood?lang=eng">Pride and the Priesthood:15-17,27</reference>
    <body>
      <image url="https://assets.ldscdn.org/a6/7e/a67ea44e15c8baa2ee172db318027cb6fb68121a/dieter_f_uchtdorf_lds.jpeg" />
      <title>Pride and the Priesthood</title>
      <highlight>Pride is a deadly cancer. It is a gateway sin that leads to a host of other human weaknesses. In fact, it could be said that every other sin is, in essence, a manifestation of pride.</highlight>
      <highlight>This sin has many faces. It leads some to revel in their own perceived self-worth, accomplishments, talents, wealth, or position. They count these blessings as evidence of being “chosen,” “superior,” or “more righteous” than others. This is the sin of “Thank God I am more special than you.” At its core is the desire to be admired or envied. It is the sin of self-glorification.</highlight>
      <highlight>For others, pride turns to envy: they look bitterly at those who have better positions, more talents, or greater possessions than they do. They seek to hurt, diminish, and tear down others in a misguided and unworthy attempt at self-elevation. When those they envy stumble or suffer, they secretly cheer.</highlight>
      <highlight>In this, as in all things, Jesus Christ is our perfect example. Whereas Lucifer tried to change the Father’s plan of salvation and obtain honor for himself, the Savior said, “Father, thy will be done, and the glory be thine forever.” Despite His magnificent abilities and accomplishments, the Savior was always meek and humble.</highlight>
    </body>
  </resource>
  <resource id="21">
    <topic>obedience</topic>
    <reference url="https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/study/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/3.7?lang=eng#p7">1 Nephi 3:7</reference>
    <body>
      <title>1 Nephi 3</title>
      <highlight verse="7">And it came to pass that I, Nephi, said unto my father: I will go and do the things which the Lord hath commanded, for I know that the Lord giveth no commandments unto the children of men, save he shall prepare a way for them that they may accomplish the thing which he commandeth them.</highlight>
    </body>
  </resource>
  <resource id="22">
    <topic>obedience</topic>
    <topic>diligence</topic>
    <reference url="https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/study/scriptures/nt/john/15.4-10?lang=eng#p4">John 15:4-10</reference>
    <body>
      <title>John 15</title>
      <highlight verse="4">Abide in me, and I in you. As the branch cannot bear fruit of itself, except it abide in the vine; no more can ye, except ye abide in me.</highlight>
      <highlight verse="5">I am the vine, ye are the branches: He that abideth in me, and I in him, the same bringeth forth much fruit: for without me ye can do nothing.</highlight>
      <highlight verse="6">If a man abide not in me, he is cast forth as a branch, and is withered; and men gather them, and cast them into the fire, and they are burned.</highlight>
      <highlight verse="7">If ye abide in me, and my words abide in you, ye shall ask what ye will, and it shall be done unto you.</highlight>
      <highlight verse="8">Herein is my Father glorified, that ye bear much fruit; so shall ye be my disciples.</highlight>
      <highlight verse="9">As the Father hath loved me, so have I loved you: continue ye in my love.</highlight>
      <highlight verse="10">If ye keep my commandments, ye shall abide in my love; even as I have kept my Father’s commandments, and abide in his love.</highlight>
    </body>
  </resource>
  <resource id="23">
    <topic>hope</topic>
    <topic>happiness</topic>
    <reference url="https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/study/scriptures/nt/john/16.31-33?lang=eng#p31">John 16:31-33</reference>
    <body>
      <title>John 16</title>
      <highlight verse="31">Jesus answered them, Do ye now believe?</highlight>
      <highlight verse="32">Behold, the hour cometh, yea, is now come, that ye shall be scattered, every man to his own, and shall leave me alone: and yet I am not alone, because the Father is with me.</highlight>
      <highlight verse="33">These things I have spoken unto you, that in me ye might have peace. In the world ye shall have tribulation: but be of good cheer; I have overcome the world.</highlight>
    </body>
  </resource>
  <resource id="24">
    <topic>happiness</topic>
    <topic>opposition</topic>
    <reference url="https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/study/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/2.11-13?lang=eng#p11">2 Nephi 2:11-13</reference>
    <body>
      <title>2 Nephi 2</title>
      <highlight verse="11">For it must needs be, that there is an opposition in all things. If not so, my firstborn in the wilderness, righteousness could not be brought to pass, neither wickedness, neither holiness nor misery, neither good nor bad. Wherefore, all things must needs be a compound in one; wherefore, if it should be one body it must needs remain as dead, having no life neither death, nor corruption nor incorruption, happiness nor misery, neither sense nor insensibility.</highlight>
      <highlight verse="12">Wherefore, it must needs have been created for a thing of naught; wherefore there would have been no purpose in the end of its creation. Wherefore, this thing must needs destroy the wisdom of God and his eternal purposes, and also the power, and the mercy, and the justice of God.</highlight>
      <highlight verse="13">And if ye shall say there is no law, ye shall also say there is no sin. If ye shall say there is no sin, ye shall also say there is no righteousness. And if there be no righteousness there be no happiness. And if there be no righteousness nor happiness there be no punishment nor misery. And if these things are not there is no God. And if there is no God we are not, neither the earth; for there could have been no creation of things, neither to act nor to be acted upon; wherefore, all things must have vanished away.</highlight>
    </body>
  </resource>
  <resource id="25">
    <topic>happiness</topic>
    <topic>obedience</topic>
    <reference url="https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/study/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/2.40-41?lang=eng#p40">Mosiah 2:40-41</reference>
    <body>
      <title>Mosiah 2</title>
      <highlight verse="40">O, all ye old men, and also ye young men, and you little children who can understand my words, for I have spoken plainly unto you that ye might understand, I pray that ye should awake to a remembrance of the awful situation of those that have fallen into transgression.</highlight>
      <highlight verse="41">And moreover, I would desire that ye should consider on the blessed and happy state of those that keep the commandments of God. For behold, they are blessed in all things, both temporal and spiritual; and if they hold out faithful to the end they are received into heaven, that thereby they may dwell with God in a state of never-ending happiness. O remember, remember that these things are true; for the Lord God hath spoken it.</highlight>
    </body>
  </resource>
  <resource id="26">
    <topic>opposition</topic>
    <reference url="https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/study/scriptures/bofm/alma/42.14-16?lang=eng#p14">Alma 42:14-16</reference>
    <body>
      <title>Alma 42</title>
      <highlight verse="14">And thus we see that all mankind were fallen, and they were in the grasp of justice; yea, the justice of God, which consigned them forever to be cut off from his presence.</highlight>
      <highlight verse="15">And now, the plan of mercy could not be brought about except an atonement should be made; therefore God himself atoneth for the sins of the world, to bring about the plan of mercy, to appease the demands of justice, that God might be a perfect, just God, and a merciful God also.</highlight>
      <highlight verse="16">Now, repentance could not come unto men except there were a punishment, which also was eternal as the life of the soul should be, affixed opposite to the plan of happiness, which was as eternal also as the life of the soul.</highlight>
    </body>
  </resource>
  <resource id="28">
    <topic>opposition</topic>
    <reference url="https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/study/scriptures/nt/james/1.2-4?lang=eng#p2">James 1:2-4</reference>
    <body>
      <title>James 1</title>
      <highlight verse="2">My brethren, count it all joy when ye fall into divers temptations;</highlight>
      <highlight verse="3">Knowing this, that the trying of your faith worketh patience.</highlight>
      <highlight verse="4">But let patience have her perfect work, that ye may be perfect and entire, wanting nothing.</highlight>
    </body>
  </resource>
  <resource id="29">
    <topic>hope</topic>
    <topic>obedience</topic>
    <topic>truth</topic>
    <reference url="https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/study/scriptures/nt/john/14.15-18?lang=eng#p15">John 14:15-18</reference>
    <body>
      <title>John 14</title>
      <highlight verse="15">If ye love me, keep my commandments.</highlight>
      <highlight verse="16">And I will pray the Father, and he shall give you another Comforter, that he may abide with you for ever;</highlight>
      <highlight verse="17">Even the Spirit of truth; whom the world cannot receive, because it seeth him not, neither knoweth him: but ye know him; for he dwelleth with you, and shall be in you.</highlight>
      <highlight verse="18">I will not leave you comfortless: I will come to you.</highlight>
    </body>
  </resource>
  <resource id="30">
    <topic>truth</topic>
    <topic>charity</topic>
    <reference url="https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/study/scriptures/nt/1-cor/13.4-7?lang=eng#p4">1 Corinthians 13:4-7</reference>
    <body>
      <title>1 Corinthians 13</title>
      <highlight verse="4">Charity suffereth long, and is kind; charity envieth not; charity vaunteth not itself, is not puffed up,</highlight>
      <highlight verse="5">Doth not behave itself unseemly, seeketh not her own, is not easily provoked, thinketh no evil;</highlight>
      <highlight verse="6">Rejoiceth not in iniquity, but rejoiceth in the truth;</highlight>
      <highlight verse="7">Beareth all things, believeth all things, hopeth all things, endureth all things.</highlight>
    </body>
  </resource>
  <resource id="31">
    <topic>truth</topic>
    <topic>obedience</topic>
    <reference url="https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/study/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/16.1-4?lang=eng#p1">1 Nephi 16:1-4</reference>
    <body>
      <title>1 Nephi 16</title>
      <highlight verse="1">And now it came to pass that after I, Nephi, had made an end of speaking to my brethren, behold they said unto me: Thou hast declared unto us hard things, more than we are able to bear.</highlight>
      <highlight verse="2">And it came to pass that I said unto them that I knew that I had spoken hard things against the wicked, according to the truth; and the righteous have I justified, and testified that they should be lifted up at the last day; wherefore, the guilty taketh the truth to be hard, for it cutteth them to the very center.</highlight>
      <highlight verse="3">And now my brethren, if ye were righteous and were willing to hearken to the truth, and give heed unto it, that ye might walk uprightly before God, then ye would not murmur because of the truth, and say: Thou speakest hard things against us.</highlight>
      <highlight verse="4">And it came to pass that I, Nephi, did exhort my brethren, with all diligence, to keep the commandments of the Lord.</highlight>
    </body>
  </resource>
</library>