<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<library lang="eng">
  <resource id="0">
    <topic>faith</topic>
    <reference url="https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/study/scriptures/bofm/alma/32.21?lang=eng#p21">Alma 32:21</reference>
    <body>
      <image url="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/gospel-library/manual/09410/1032863.jpg" />
      <video url="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dRvBgxKkbB0" />
      <title>Alma 32</title>
      <highlight verse="21">And now as I said concerning faith—faith is not to have a perfect knowledge of things; therefore if ye have faith ye hope for things which are not seen, which are true.</highlight>
    </body>
  </resource>
  <resource id="1">
    <topic>faith</topic>
    <reference url="https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/study/scriptures/nt/matt/17.20?lang=eng#p20">Matthew 17:20</reference>
    <body>
      <title>Matthew 17</title>
      <highlight verse="20">And Jesus said unto them, Because of your unbelief: for verily I say unto you, If ye have faith as a grain of mustard seed, ye shall say unto this mountain, Remove hence to yonder place; and it shall remove; and nothing shall be impossible unto you.</highlight>
    </body>
  </resource>
  <resource id="2">
    <topic>faith</topic>
    <reference url="https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/study/scriptures/nt/james/2.14-24?lang=eng#p14">James 2:14-24</reference>
    <body>
      <title>James 2</title>
      <highlight verse="14">What doth it profit, my brethren, though a man say he hath faith, and have not works? can faith save him?</highlight>
      <highlight verse="17">Even so faith, if it hath not works, is dead, being alone.</highlight>
      <highlight verse="18">Yea, a man may say, Thou hast faith, and I have works: shew me thy faith without thy works, and I will shew thee my faith by my works.</highlight>
      <highlight verse="19">Thou believest that there is one God; thou doest well: the devils also believe, and tremble.</highlight>
      <highlight verse="24">Ye see then how that by works a man is justified, and not by faith only.</highlight>
    </body>
  </resource>
  <resource id="3">
    <topic>diligence</topic>
    <reference url="https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/study/scriptures/bofm/moro/9.6?lang=eng#p6">Moroni 9:6</reference>
    <body>
      <title>Moroni 9</title>
      <highlight verse="6">And now, my beloved son, notwithstanding their hardness, let us labor diligently; for if we should cease to labor, we should be brought under condemnation; for we have a labor to perform whilst in this tabernacle of clay, that we may conquer the enemy of all righteousness, and rest our souls in the kingdom of God.</highlight>
    </body>
  </resource>
  <resource id="8">
    <topic>charity</topic>
    <reference url="https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/study/scriptures/bofm/moro/7.45-48?lang=eng#p45">Moroni 7:45-48</reference>
    <body>
      <title>Moroni 7</title>
      <highlight verse="45">And charity suffereth long, and is kind, and envieth not, and is not puffed up, seeketh not her own, is not easily provoked, thinketh no evil, and rejoiceth not in iniquity but rejoiceth in the truth, beareth all things, believeth all things, hopeth all things, endureth all things.</highlight>
      <highlight verse="46">Wherefore, my beloved brethren, if ye have not charity, ye are nothing, for charity never faileth. Wherefore, cleave unto charity, which is the greatest of all, for all things must fail—</highlight>
      <highlight verse="47">But charity is the pure love of Christ, and it endureth forever; and whoso is found possessed of it at the last day, it shall be well with him.</highlight>
      <highlight verse="48">Wherefore, my beloved brethren, pray unto the Father with all the energy of heart, that ye may be filled with this love, which he hath bestowed upon all who are true followers of his Son, Jesus Christ; that ye may become the sons of God; that when he shall appear we shall be like him, for we shall see him as he is; that we may have this hope; that we may be purified even as he is pure. Amen.</highlight>
    </body>
  </resource>
  <resource id="5">
    <topic>faith</topic>
    <reference url="https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/study/scriptures/bofm/ether/12.6?lang=eng#p6">Ether 12:6</reference>
    <body>
      <title>Ether 12</title>
      <highlight verse="6">And now, I, Moroni, would speak somewhat concerning these things; I would show unto the world that faith is things which are hoped for and not seen; wherefore, dispute not because ye see not, for ye receive no witness until after the trial of your faith.</highlight>
    </body>
  </resource>
  <resource id="6">
    <topic>diligence</topic>
    <reference url="https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/study/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/4.26-27?lang=eng#p26">Mosiah 4:26-27</reference>
    <body>
      <title>Mosiah 4</title>
      <highlight verse="26">And now, for the sake of these things which I have spoken unto you—that is, for the sake of retaining a remission of your sins from day to day, that ye may walk guiltless before God—I would that ye should impart of your substance to the poor, every man according to that which he hath, such as feeding the hungry, clothing the naked, visiting the sick and administering to their relief, both spiritually and temporally, according to their wants.</highlight>
      <highlight verse="27">And see that all these things are done in wisdom and order; for it is not requisite that a man should run faster than he has strength. And again, it is expedient that he should be diligent, that thereby he might win the prize; therefore, all things must be done in order.</highlight>
    </body>
  </resource>
  <resource id="7">
    <topic>diligence</topic>
    <reference url="https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/study/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/127.4?lang=eng#p4">D&amp;C 127:4</reference>
    <body>
      <title>Doctrine and Covenants 127</title>
      <highlight verse="4">And again, verily thus saith the Lord: Let the work of my temple, and all the works which I have appointed unto you, be continued on and not cease; and let your diligence, and your perseverance, and patience, and your works be redoubled, and you shall in nowise lose your reward, saith the Lord of Hosts. And if they persecute you, so persecuted they the prophets and righteous men that were before you. For all this there is a reward in heaven.</highlight>
    </body>
  </resource>
  <resource id="9">
    <topic>charity</topic>
    <reference url="https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/study/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/19.9?lang=eng#p9">1 Nephi 19:9</reference>
    <body>
      <title>1 Nephi 19</title>
      <highlight verse="9">And the world, because of their iniquity, shall judge him to be a thing of naught; wherefore they scourge him, and he suffereth it; and they smite him, and he suffereth it. Yea, they spit upon him, and he suffereth it, because of his loving kindness and his long-suffering towards the children of men.</highlight>
    </body>
  </resource>
  <resource id="10">
    <topic>charity</topic>
    <reference url="https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/study/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/2.17?lang=eng#p17">Mosiah 2:17</reference>
    <body>
      <title>Mosiah 2</title>
      <highlight verse="17">And behold, I tell you these things that ye may learn wisdom; that ye may learn that when ye are in the service of your fellow beings ye are only in the service of your God.</highlight>
    </body>
  </resource>
</library>